Finding Aid for Literary Adelphi (University of Michigan) records, 1857-1939
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Literary Adelphi (University of Michigan) records 1857-1939
Literary Adelphi (University of Michigan).
2 linear feet
87217 Bimu F21 2
Records, 1857-1939, of the Literary Adelphi, student literary organization at the University of Michigan; include minutes, constitution and bylaws, literary essays, financial records, correspondence, and membership material.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were received from the University of Michigan Library (donor number 1278 ).
The record group is open without restriction.
The Adelphi literary society was formed in 1857 after the demise of Phi Phi Alpha, the first literary society to be organized on the University of Michigan campus. The traditional programs of these societies were largely orations, essays and debates.
The records of Literary Adelphi are organized in two series by format: Unbound Records and Bound Records.
Unbound Records includes minutes (1857-1860), records (1857-1860), correspondence (1890-1897), miscellaneous, and constitution and bylaws.
Bound Records includes three volumes of Hesperian, the organization's literary magazine, six volumes of record books, two volumes of library records, and five volumes of treasurer's books and membership lists.
Subjects:
Literature--Societies, etc.--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Students--Societies, etc.
- Unbound records
  - Minutes, 1857-1860 (Box 1)
  - Records, 1857-1860 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1890-1897 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Constitution and bylaws, 1877 (Box 1)
- Bound records
  - Hesperian, 1857-1863, 3 volumes (Box 1)
  - Record book
    - 1857-1814, 3 volumes (Box 1)
    - 1921-1939, 3 volumes (Box 2)
  - Records of the library, 2 volumes (Box 2)
  - Treasurer's books and membership list, 5 volumes (Box 2)